Luke Belliveau

Software Engineer

USA, Hungary lukebelliveau.dev github.com/lukebelliveau hi@lukebelliveau.dev +1-617-275-2452 Luke is a software delivery consultant with seven years of experience engineering full stack web applications and services at enterprise scale. If you need to get an application built or some code untangled, there's a good chance he can help.

Tools

Languages & Databases TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Python, Golang, C#

Databases Firebase Realtime DB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Cassandra

Deploy, Automation, Hosting AWS, Digital Ocean, Firebase, Jenkins, Spinnaker, GitHub Actions, Vercel

Web Frameworks & Build Tooling React, Next.js, Redux, Vite, Auth0, Konva, Highcharts

Testing Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Vitest, Cypress, Jest,

JUnit, Chai / Mocha, Selenium

Work Experience —

Consultant Software Engineer NuWave Technologies

2021 - Current

Luke managed the development and maintenance of NuWave's suite of web applications. With NuWave, he:

- Led development of the Prizm API Gateway management console on a team of three developers to a successful launch, built on Jenkins/AWS EC2 and deployed to AWS S3
- Engineered a seamless migration from AngularJS to React for NuWave's LightWave Client and Server products, reducing total lines of source code by 35%. Built with Vite.
- Created new automated testing pipelines and ran workshops & training, facilitated a culture of testing & CI, building up company-wide front-end code coverage from 0% to over 95% with Vitest, Jest and Cypress
- Played an instrumental role in the interview, evaluation & mentorship process of new hires

Technical Partner ZUUT.co 2020 - Current

Luke collaborated with ZUUT's founder, working from the product's inception through a successful launch. Handling all facets of development, he:

- Built a full-fledged interactive computer-aided design web application, enabling users to save, share and collaborate in real time on gardening plots featuring a deep interaction & collision detection engine
- Designed and implemented an account and data management system using Firebase services such as Authentication, Realtime DB and Cloud Storage
- Implemented system & interface for users to compare, contrast and purchase equipment for their grow designs featuring an affiliate link system using Amazon's APIs, successfully qualifying ZUUT for Amazon's Associate's Program
- Integrated content management systems enabling nontechnical users to update item metadata and create blog content with a simple interface, using Airtable and Contentful
- · Hired & managed a team of freelance developers & designers to accelerate development

On Grubhub's Cloud Infrastructure team, Luke designed & implemented frameworks, tools, & services that enabled web, mobile, & site reliability engineers to do their jobs as efficiently as they can. In his time at GrubHub, he:

- Engineered changes to core framework to facilitate communication between microservices in a new Envoy service mesh architecture
- Led integration of SMS service with a new provider, handling the development, evaluation, & communication with stakeholders on both ends
- Ownership of Notifications stack of microservices in Java (with Guice & Spring), spanning SMS, mobile push, email, & fax functionalities
- Built a service in React & Python used by Site Reliability Engineers to view system status & make changes during outages
- Designed the architecture & database schemas for a new notifications platform. This service was used by product & marketing teams at GrubHub to manage notifications for email, SMS, push, & fax.

Senior Software Engineer

Thoughtworks

ThoughtWorks

2017 - 2018

As a Senior Engineer at ThoughtWorks, Luke worked on software teams servicing clients in e-commerce & cybersecurity. In this role, Luke:

- Built a dashboard for analysts to monitor web traffic with rich interactions and data visualizations, built with Vue & Highcharts
- Facilitated front-end training sessions for the company, coordinating speakers & workshops for bimonthly meetups in a global community of React & Vue developers
- Designed APIs & data pipelines to facilitate a seamless integration of Kroger's e-commerce platform with a newly acquired subsidiary
- Worked with designers & executive stakeholders to determine key features/specifications & break them into manageable tasks
- Developed a backend-for-frontend in Golang to aggregate, analyze & perform transformations on repositories of logs before serving them to the client, improving performance

Associate Software Engineer

2016 - 2017

Luke began his career as an Associate Software Engineer at ThoughtWorks, where he was deployed on a software delivery team at one of the largest health insurance firms in the United States. In this role, his achievements include:

- Delivering a full-stack application in JavaScript+React & Java, serving as the interface for users to apply for coverage & request changes
- Serving as a front-end specialist, participating in architecture meetings & facilitating weekly discussions about React & JavaScript topics
- Mentoring new hires, providing weekly office hours & coaching sessions

Freelance Projects

https://selenium.dev

2019

Given a set of mockups, I delivered a new website for Selenium, a popular browser automation tool. Built with Jekyll & Hugo.

Devil's Dice Game 2018

Devil's Dice is an exciting mobile game where users place a phone on the table & face various challenges based on a virtual dice roll. This app has a special place in my heart - a year after its release, I noticed a group of travelers playing the game in the kitchen at a hostel in Slovakia! It remains active today & enjoys a 4.5-star rating on the Google Play Store with over 10,000 downloads.

SATURATION - BROCKHAMPTON

2017

Official application for world-famous boyband BROCKHAMPTON, designed to release music videos & other exclusive goodies before their general release to external platforms. With over 10,000 downloads, SATURATION enjoyed a rating of 5 stars on the Google Play store, where it was active from 2017-2019.

Education